<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The proceedings at the Kings-Bench-Bar upon the execution of the writ of enquiry of damages at the suit of His Royal Highness the Duke of York, against Titus (formerly stild doctor) Oates.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B28395</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886876</idno>
  <idno type="VID">189594</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240887127</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P3561</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 515.l.2[99]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226725</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886876</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886876e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B28395)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 189594)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C17:1[100])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The proceedings at the Kings-Bench-Bar upon the execution of the writ of enquiry of damages at the suit of His Royal Highness the Duke of York, against Titus (formerly stild doctor) Oates.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Sold at the entrance into the Old-Spring-Garden,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1684.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Oates, Titus, 1649-1705 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Popish Plot, 1678 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Charles II, 1660-1685 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Maria Cecilia Caride</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="court_proceedings">
            <pb facs="tcp:189594:1"/>
            <head>THE Proceedings at the Kings-Bench-Bar Upon the Execution of the Writ of Enquiry of Damages At the SUIT of His ROYAL HIGHNESS the DUKE of <hi>YORK,</hi> AGAINST TITUS (formerly stild Doctor) OATES.</head>
            <p>THis day being the last day of <hi>Trinity-Term,</hi> was a Writ of Enqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of Damages at the <hi>Kings-Bench-Bar,</hi> in an Action upon the Statute <hi>deScandalis magnatum,</hi> at the Suit of His Royal Highness the Duke of <hi>York</hi> against <hi>Titus Oates;</hi> who denying to plead, suffer'd Judgment upon him by <hi>nil dicit:</hi> And in regard of the Eminency of the Person who is Plaintiff, and of the Notoriousness of the Defendant, it was pray'd by His R. Highness's Council, <hi>That for the more solemnity of the matter, and to sa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>isfie all persons who may be curious to pique at the Proceedings at Law, that it should be try d at the</hi> Kings-Bench-Bar, <hi>though it be a thing very unusual, being ordinarily done before the Sheriff in his County.</hi> There appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red a very substantial Jury of Knights, Esquires, and Gentlemen, to the number of Fifteen, who without going from the Bar, (as well upon the words within the Record, as upon the Evidence of a great number of worthy and credible Witnesses, which strengthen'd it) gave Damages to His Royal Highness of 100000 <hi>l.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Lord-Chief-Justice most faithfully and learnedly summ'd up the Evidence, and descanted upon the evil consequences that attended such Insolence as presumed to reproach and calumniate the Peers of the Realm, more especially a person so near and dear to the King and Crown as His Royal Highness, whom the said <hi>Oates</hi> hath be spatterd and traduc'd in all Companies he came into, since the beginning of his <hi>Evidenceship</hi> in 78. calling him <hi>Traytor, Rascal,</hi> and such-like horrid names, and charging Him with being in the <hi>Plot,</hi> with firing the City, and raising the Army at <hi>Black-Heath,</hi> in order to introduce Popery, and cut all the True Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testants Throats. He likewise was pleas d to give him the Epithet of a <hi>Son of a W</hi>—; And after preaching in the City, being invited by some of his Auditory to a Glass of Wine, he asked them, <hi>If any of them ever eat or drank with</hi> York? (because His Royal Highness had done that Royal Favour to some of the Societies of the City to Honour them with His presence) but <hi>Oates</hi> told them, <hi>If any of them did, he would not eat or drink with any that eat or drank with the Devil.</hi> He left them, and went to a Braziers House, (his Face having a Sympathy with the Calling.) Ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Gospel-expression of his at <hi>Oxford</hi> was, <hi>That he hop'd if the Devil had had one place hotter than other in Hell, he would reserve it for the Duke of</hi> Y—. Much more of the <hi>No Doctor</hi>'s stuff of this kind was sworn against him, and without difficulty believed by the Jury; which is a means to secure his present Lodgings, until he is removed by some extraordinary means, which probably may soon happen.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Sold at the Entrance into the <hi>Old-Spring-Garden,</hi> 1684.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>